

\((+234) 802 245 8666 | \(\infty \) olayinkav28@gmail.com | \(\oldsymbol{O} \) iYinka | \(\infty \) iamyinka | \(\overline{\mathbb{B}} \) portfolio

"To make a change start with the man in the mirror."

Summary

I am a punctilious and self-motivated software engineer with demonstrated experience in improving software performance, testing and updating existing software, and helping in writing readable and reusable codes. With a great passion for personal growth and software development, offers a proven track record of sensational achievements, and strong attention to detail. Capable of learning from more experienced developers. Continuously finding ways to maximize user experience with eagerness to tackle complex problems on schedule and within budget.

Skills

Front-end React/S, JavaScript, Typescript, Next/S, Git, Redux, HTML5, CSS, Tailwind CSS, Figma, MUI, Ant Design

Back-end NodeJS, ExpressJS

Platforms Github, Gitlab, Netlify, Heroku

DevOps AWS, Cloudformation, Docker, CircleCI

Database MongoDB, Firebase, Sanity

Languages English, Yorùbá

Experience

Ace of Spades Consult Limited

Abuja, Nigeria

Front-end Engineer (Remote, Contract)

Dec. 2021 - PRESENT

- Responsible for 79% redesign, development, and implementation of APIs, and remote hosting of software applications responsible for accrued VAT audit, verification, and aggregation for merchants such as Multichoice Nigeria, Startimes, and ISPs amongst others as needed by the FIRS Nigeria.
- Tested and updated new features of about 45% of the existing software using my knowledge and expertise and made improvement suggestions.
- Working knowledge of configuration management and version control tools
- Remotely configured on-premises FIRS' Windows Server 2016 to conveniently host software applications (client-side).
- Created Dockerfile for building docker images.
- Implemented Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery using CircleCI, Netlify, and Git.

Exalt Application Limited

Feb. 2021 - Jan. 2022

Front-end Engineer (Hybrid)

- Responsible for on-time delivery of high-quality code.
- Assigned with the conversion of UI/UX designs and building reusable components; check on team members and the backend engineers for necessary APIs and restructuring.
- Worked on multiple software projects simultaneously and participated in the whole software development process from design to implementation and delivery.
- Implemented a live tracking system of parcels in transit using Google Maps API.
- Implemented Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery using Netlify, and Git.

Zsoftbase

Dec. 2020 - Jan. 2021

Full-stack Engineer (Remote, Internship)

Contributed to the front and back ends features of a high school's web application designed to take all academic records activities of staff and students.

Gosslink Engineering Limited

Field Technician Intern (Students Industrial Work Experience Scheme, SIWES)

Lagos, Nigeria

Oct. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Programmed and configured prepaid meters to monitor electrical power distribution across Lagos State under the Eko
 Electricity Distribution Company (EKEDC), Nigeria using network providers (Airtel in this case).
- Responsible for the inspection of power distribution sites for necessary upgrades required.

Loyalty Solutions Limited

Lagos, Nigeri

Customer Service Representative (Full time**)**

May 2012 - Jan. 2014

Tasked using company-based software applications at the Airtel office over front desk-related issues; helping customers with respective needs such as sim cards retrievals, registrations, connection with the service provider (Airtel Nigeria), Know-Your-Customer (KYC), and other technical needs concerning the individual customer.

TeeLink CompuTech

Lagos, Nigeria

Technician (*Trainee***)**

Jul. 2010 - Apr. 2012

- Sufficiently equipped with the use, installation, upgrade and downgrade of a variety of software for clients for their computer system's compatibility.
- Adequately learned to install and repair computer hardware for both corporate and individual business owners.

Education

Udacity

Lagos, Nigeria

Nanodegree, ALX-T Cloud DevOps Engineer

May 2022 - Aug. 2022

- Created, configured, and secured (with IAM) S3 bucket. Distributed websites via CloudFront. Deployed static website on AWS.
- Deployed infrastructure as Code (IAC):
 - Adequately used CloudFormation to create a formidable infrastructure consisting of VPCs, subnets, EC2 instances, SSGs, GWs, and more
 - Explored the use of Lucid Chart in converting business requirements into infrastructure diagrams with an understanding of the principles behind the design choice.
 - Efficiently utilized two different types of AWS storage options for a web application architecture: Relation Database
 Storage (RDS) service and Object storage service Simple Storage Service (S3)
- Built CI/CD Pipelines, Monitoring & Logging
- Implemented Microservices at Scale using AWS & Kubernetes; used Docker format containers.

University of Lagos (UniLag) B. Sc. IN APPLIED PHYSICS

Lagos, Nigeria

Sep. 2014 - Nov. 2018

- Developed software to execute basic mathematical tasks.
 - Developed and programmed a Smoke and Fire Alarm System as a safety measure for homes and office spaces.
 - Imparted with practical skills and the imagination to design complex experiments.
 - Drilled in being strong in mathematical skills, methods, and logical reasoning toward passionate problem solving and how things work.
 - Familiarity with and the ability to use a range of manual and computerized equipment.

Honor & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

2022 **Recipient**, ALX-T Cloud DevOps Engineer scholarship

Online, Udacity

DOMESTIC

2009 Awardee, Baptist High School best graduating student

Lagos, Nigeria

2008 1st Place, Lagos' State-Wide Essay Competition on HIV/AIDS awareness.

Lagos, Nigeria

Certifications & Achievements

INTERNATIONAL

2020 The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp

2020 PHP for Beginners – Become a PHP Master – CMS Project

Online, Udemy Online, Udemy

DOMESTIC

2015 Advanced Occupational Safety and Health Course

Lagos, Nigeria

Leadership & Involvements

Ace of Spades Consult Limited

Abuja, Nigeria

Lead Front-end Engineer

- Supervised the team on project reviews.
- Reviewed codebase for features optimization.

Exalt Application Limited

Lagos, Nigeria

Lead Front-end Engineer

- Headed the Front-end team on newly added features introduced to four (4) software applications for clients' and customers' better user experience.
- Oversaw and reviewed codes from two frontend developers.

Ref	eren	ces
-----	------	-----

Available upon request.